let questions = [
  {
      numb: 1,
      question: "If Sn denotes the sum of the first n terms in an AP and S1:S4=1:10 then the ratio of first term to fourth term is ___",
      answer: "1:4",
      options: [
        "1:3",
        "2:3",
        "1:4",
        "1:5"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 2,
      question: "Two people agree to meet on January 9, 2005 between 6 PM to 7 PM, with the understanding that each will wait no longer than 20 min for the other. What is the probability that they will meet ?",
      answer: "4/9",
      options: [
        "5/9",
        "7/9",
        "2/9",
        "4/9"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 3,
      question: "ABCD is a trapezium, such that AB, DC are parallel and BC is perpendicular to them. If ÐDAB = 450, BC=2 cm and CD = 3 cm then AB = __.",
      answer: "5 cm",
      options: [
        "3 cm",
        "5 cn",
        "4 cm",
        "2 cn"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 4,
      question: "In a cricket match, Team A scored 232 runs without losing wicket. The score consisted of byes, wides and runs scored by two opening batsmen: Ram and Shyam. The runs scored by the two batsmen are 26 times wides. There are 8 more byes than wides. If the ratio of the runs scored by Ram and Shyam is 6:7, then the runs scored by Ram is ___.",
      answer: "96",
      options: [
        "88",
        "96",
        "102",
        "112"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 5,
      question: "If 0 < p < 1, then roots of the equation (1-p)x^2 + 4x + p = 0 are __.",
      answer: "Real and both negative",
      options: [
        "Both 0",
        "Imaginary",
        "Real and both positive",
        "Real and both negative"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 6,
      question: "For real numbers p, q and a, if the polynomial x^3 – 3px + 2q is divisible by the polynomial x^2+2ax + a^2, then which of the polynomial x^2 +2ax + a^2, then which of the following is correct ?",
      answer: "P^3 = q^2",
      options: [
        "3p=2q",
        "P^2 = q^3",
        "P^3 = q^2",
        "27p^3 = 4q^2"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 7,
      question: "The value of (3^(1/2) – 1)( 3^(1/2) + 3^(1/4) + 1)( 3^(1/2) - 3^(1/4) + 1) is _____.",
      answer: "3sqrt(3) –1",
      options: [
        "3sqrt(3)",
        "1",
        "3sqrt(3) –1",
        "3sqrt(3) +1"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 8,
      question: "Given that the system of equations mx + 2y = 10 ; 3x – 2y = 0 have the integer solution. Then the possible values of m are",
      answer: "-2,2, -8",
      options: [
        "-2,2, -8",
        "2 , 8, -2",
        "2, -8, 8",
        "-2 , 8, 1"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 9,
      question: "Consider an arithmetic progression with n terms. If the common difference is increased by 1, then nth term increased by 19. If the 5th term of the progression is 28 and the average of the first and last terms is 61, then the 10th term is ____.",
      answer: "58",
      options: [
        "51",
        "58",
        "56",
        "60"
      ]
    },
    {
      numb: 10,
      question: "The ages of the members of a club are in AP with difference 3 months. The sum of ages of all the members is 300 years and the youngest member is a child of 9 years. The age of the eldest member = ___.",
      answer: "15 years",
      options: [
        "12 years",
        "13 years",
        "15 years",
        "14 years"
      ]
    },

];